Contact

devsques@ukr.net

www.linkedin.com/in/vitaliylitvinenko (LinkedIn) beardeddev.pp.ua (Personal) github.com/beardeddev/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills
ASP.NET MVC
Web Development
ASP.NET

Languages

English (Elementary)
Russian (Native or Bilingual)
Ukrainian (Native or Bilingual)

Vitaliy Litvinenko

Web Developer at SDL Ukraine

Summary

Strong experience in applying of object-oriented paradigm in practice. Experience in design and implementation of 3-tier and MVC/HMVC/MVT applications, analysis of domain, data storage, data access layer, code generation, object relational mappers, domain business logic design and implementation. Server side application architecture. High traffic applications profiling and perfomance optimization. Web applications components and client side logic implementation, W3C compliant optimization, usability, SEO. Experience with 3-5 developers leadership.

Specialties:

ASP .NET MVC: design, implementation, configuration, deployment IIS, modular applications, AOP, REST WebServices. ADO .Net, perforance optimization.

Design and implementation of data storage, data access layer, domain buisness logic. RDBMS profiling, optimization. ORM & DAL codegeneration.

Client side scripting. Unobtrusive JavaScript. Ajax Web UI. Search engine optimization, GUI Usability.

WCMS and content centric website development.

Language/framework agnostic web application architecture.

Experience

SDL Tridion Development Lab Ukraine | SDL Ukraine Web Developer

July 2011 - May 2019 (7 years 11 months)

Kiev, Ukraine

- Design and implementation of web applications on top of a Tridion WCMS + DD4T + ASP .NET MVC stack;
- Architecture and implementation of core logic, GUI, extensions, integration with 3rd party applications (Salesforce, Marketo);
- Rewrite/porting of obsolete parts and web applications to a new stack;
- Partly managing team in the role of an SM;

Ukrainian Media Holding Web Developer May 2007 - July 2011 (4 years 3 months) Ukraine, Kiev

- Architecture, design and implementation of web application and services
 ASP .NET / C#;
- · Client side web development;
- Design and implementation of content centric websites;
- Domain analisys, design of data storage, application architecture design.

Projects:

- football.ua (developer)
- tv.ua (developer)
- focus.in.ua (lead developer)
- kinokino.com.ua (lead developer, project/team lead)
- 100m2.com.ua (lead developer, project/team lead)
- dengi.ua (lead developer)

V.M. Glushkov Institute of Cybernetics of NAS of Ukraine Software engineer of GIS Technologies January 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 5 months)

Ukraine, Kiev

- · Implementation of data visualization software;
- · Implementation of mathematical models in GIS;

Kyiv Municipal Advisory and Diagnostic Centre Software Engineer of Statistics and Analysis Department February 2003 - January 2007 (4 years)

Ukraine, Kyiv

- Design and implementation statistical data analysis part of software;
- Re-engineering of legacy modules and databases, adaptation, support;
- Development of the analytical software;

Engineer at Computing Department

- · LAN administration, DB management;
- Technical support of workstations, servers, peripherals, LAN;
- Software support;

Education

National Aviation University

Specialist, Software of automated systems · (2001 - 2007)

97

· (1993 - 2000)